<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>I'd vote for Hillary, but... | Hillary Myths</title>
    <description>&amp;ldquo;I'd vote for Hillary, but...&amp;rdquo; is a site designed to refute myths and misconceptions about Hillary Clinton. Please pick your concern from the following list!
</description>
    <link>https://hillarymyths.org/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://hillarymyths.org/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>isn't her experience all bad?</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;q-isnt-her-experience-all-bad&quot;&gt;Q: Isn’t her experience all bad?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;: In the first Presidential debate, Donald Trump claimed that Hillary “has experience, but it’s bad experience.” This is not true. Specifically, he was referring to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://correctrecord.org/the-path-to-a-landmark-deal-how-hillary-led-on-iran-sanctions/&quot;&gt;Iran Nuclear Deal&lt;/a&gt; and our &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.npr.org/2011/09/12/140292920/natos-intervention-in-libya-a-new-model&quot;&gt;intervention in Libya&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Far from a failure, the Iran Nuclear Deal was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/the-obama-bet-that-paid-off/2015/09/15/e46b80f6-5be6-11e5-8e9e-dce8a2a2a679_story.html?utm_term=.225e39af4806&quot;&gt;one of the most strategic successes&lt;/a&gt; of the Obama administration. And the &lt;a href=&quot;http://correctrecord.org/the-path-to-a-landmark-deal-how-hillary-led-on-iran-sanctions/&quot;&gt;crippling sanctions&lt;/a&gt; that Hillary personally fought for pushed Iran to the negotiating table.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Hillary’s critics have convinced many people that the Libyan crisis began and ended with the tragic attack on our mission in Benghazi. However, the U.S. intervention in Libya helped avert &lt;a href=&quot;http://uk.reuters.com/article/libya-protests-gaddafi-idUKLDE71L26D20110222&quot;&gt;mass killings&lt;/a&gt; by the Libyan government. It also led to the ouster and death of Moammar Gadhafi, a brutal dictator, terrorist supporter, and enemy of the United States. What if the United States had not intervened in Libya? According to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2015/03/07/libya-intervention-daalder_n_6809756.html&quot;&gt;Ivo Daalder, President of the Chicago Council on Global Affairs and the U.S. Ambassador to NATO during the 2011 Libyan revolution&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;We would have seen a massive humanitarian nightmare inflicted on the people of Libya by their government.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;q-what-were-hillarys-other-accomplishments-as-a-public-servant&quot;&gt;Q: What were Hillary’s other accomplishments as a public servant?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;: Hillary’s record as a public servant includes her time as Secretary of State, U.S. Senator from New York, First Lady of the United States, and the First Lady of Arkansas. Here are just a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hillaryclinton.com/feed/seven-hillary-clintons-biggest-accomplishments/&quot;&gt;few of her accomplishments&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;As Secretary of State, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.politico.com/story/2012/11/clinton-announces-gaza-cease-fire-084145&quot;&gt;Hillary demonstrated her “shuttle diplomacy” skills&lt;/a&gt;. During a brutal period of violence, Hillary cut short a trip to southeast Asia and flew to the region. A bus bombing struck Tel Aviv as Hillary arrived to begin an intense round of shuttle negotiations. But &lt;strong&gt;within twenty-four hours, the ceasefire went into effect&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;As Secretary of State, Hillary made &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hillaryclinton.com/issues/lgbt-equality/&quot;&gt;LGBT rights&lt;/a&gt; a focus of U.S. foreign policy. She fought for the first-ever U.N. Human Rights Council resolution on human rights and declared that &lt;strong&gt;“gay rights are human rights&lt;/strong&gt;.” She also made the State Department a &lt;strong&gt;better, fairer place for LGBT employees&lt;/strong&gt; to work.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Hillary &lt;strong&gt;worked with Republicans&lt;/strong&gt; to expand health care access for &lt;a href=&quot;http://correctrecord.org/hillary-clinton-a-record-of-service-to-veterans/&quot;&gt;members of the National Guard and reservists&lt;/a&gt;, making sure those who served and their families had &lt;strong&gt;access to health care&lt;/strong&gt; when they returned home. And she worked to &lt;strong&gt;expand the Family Medical Leave Act&lt;/strong&gt;, allowing families of those wounded in action to care for their loved ones.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Hillary had been the U.S. Senator from New York for just a few months when terrorists attacked us on 9/11. She worked tirelessly to make sure that the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nydailynews.com/news/politics/9-11-survivors-applaud-hillary-clinton-dnc-supportive-article-1.2727482&quot;&gt;9/11 first responders&lt;/a&gt; who suffered long term health effects from their time at Ground Zero &lt;strong&gt;got the care they needed&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In 1995, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/politics/first-draft/2015/09/05/20-years-later-hillary-clintons-beijing-speech-on-women-resonates/&quot;&gt;Hillary spoke at the United Nations 4th World Conference on Women&lt;/a&gt;. In this speech, she famously declared: &lt;strong&gt;If there is one message that echoes forth from this conference, let it be that human rights are women’s rights and women’s rights are human rights, once and for all!&lt;/strong&gt; As unassuming as that sounds today, declaring that “women’s rights are human rights” was very controversial at the time. Many within the U.S. government didn’t want Hillary to go to Beijing at all. Others wanted her to pick a less “polarizing” topic. But Hillary would not be deterred; she was determined to speak out about women’s issues.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When Hillary was First Lady, she fought for health care reform. When that effort did not succeed, Hillary kept fighting. &lt;strong&gt;She worked with Republicans and Democrats&lt;/strong&gt; to help create the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.factcheck.org/2008/03/giving-hillary-credit-for-schip/&quot;&gt;Children’s Health Insurance Program&lt;/a&gt;. Today, CHIP &lt;strong&gt;provides health care to more than 8 million children&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;q-so-she-only-got-into-public-service-because-she-was-bill-clintons-wife-right&quot;&gt;Q: So she only got into public service because she was Bill Clinton’s wife, right?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;: No. Hillary’s call to public service began before she married Bill. When Hillary graduated law school, she could have joined a prestigious law firm. Instead, she chose to take a job with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hillaryclinton.com/feed/what-hillary-clintons-first-job-out-of-law-school-can-tell-us-about-who-she-is-today/&quot;&gt;Children’s Defense Fund&lt;/a&gt;, where &lt;strong&gt;she worked with teenagers incarcerated in adult prisons and families with disabled children&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 13:03:32 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://hillarymyths.org/issues/bad-experience/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://hillarymyths.org/issues/bad-experience/</guid>
        
        
        <category>experience</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>doesn't she want my guns?</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;q-doesnt-hillary-want-to-take-away-my-right-to-own-a-gun&quot;&gt;Q: Doesn’t Hillary want to take away my right to own a gun?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: Hillary respects law-abiding citizens’ 2nd Amendment right to own guns. She just wants to put in place &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hillaryclinton.com/issues/gun-violence-prevention/&quot;&gt;common-sense solutions&lt;/a&gt; to make our communities safer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guns kill &lt;a href=&quot;http://fivethirtyeight.com/features/gun-deaths/&quot;&gt;around 33,000&lt;/a&gt; Americans a year. Hillary is committed to reducing the epidemic of gun violence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;q-what-do-those-solutions-look-like&quot;&gt;Q: What do those solutions look like?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: Here are the facts. As president, Hillary will:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Expand background checks.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://fivethirtyeight.com/features/most-americans-agree-with-obama-that-more-gun-buyers-should-get-background-checks/&quot;&gt;92% of Americans, including 87% of Republicans&lt;/a&gt; support expanding background checks for gun purchases. Currently, individuals can buy guns at gun shows or on the internet without a background check. Hillary will fight to pass legislation that closes these loopholes, as well as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thetrace.org/2016/06/one-year-later-and-the-loophole-that-let-the-charleston-shooter-buy-his-gun-remains-wide-open/&quot;&gt;the loophole&lt;/a&gt; which allowed a shooter to gun down nine people in Charleston, South Carolina, by avoiding a background check if the seller fails to complete the check within three days.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hold irresponsible gun dealers accountable.&lt;/strong&gt; Because of the Protection of Lawful Commerce in Arms Act, victims of gun violence &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Protection_of_Lawful_Commerce_in_Arms_Act&quot;&gt;cannot hold liable&lt;/a&gt; negligent gun dealers and manufacturers. Hillary will work to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.courant.com/politics/capitol-watch/hc-hillary-clinton-sandy-hook-guns-story.html&quot;&gt;repeal&lt;/a&gt; this law and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nbcnews.com/meet-the-press/hillary-clinton-unveil-plan-major-new-gun-restrictions-n438361&quot;&gt;revoke&lt;/a&gt; the licenses of gun dealers who knowingly sell to traffickers and straw purchasers (individuals who buy guns on behalf of violent felons).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keep guns out of the hands of violent criminals and those with severe mental illness.&lt;/strong&gt; Hillary will support laws preventing domestic abusers from buying and owning gun. She will make it a federal crime intentionally to buy a gun for a person prohibited from owning one. She will close &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2016/01/06/us/how-people-with-mental-illness-are-able-to-obtain-guns.html?_r=0&quot;&gt;loopholes&lt;/a&gt; that allow people suffering from severe mental illness to purchase and own guns. And she will work to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/post-politics/wp/2016/06/13/clinton-calls-for-a-new-assault-weapons-ban-12-years-after-the-last-one-expired/&quot;&gt;ban assault weapons.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 13:03:32 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://hillarymyths.org/issues/but-hillary-wants-my-guns/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://hillarymyths.org/issues/but-hillary-wants-my-guns/</guid>
        
        
        <category>guns,</category>
        
        <category>gun</category>
        
        <category>control</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>she isn't trustworthy.</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;q-doesnt-she-lie-all-of-the-time&quot;&gt;Q: Doesn’t she lie all of the time?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;: No. Hillary is actually &lt;strong&gt;one of the most truthful candidates&lt;/strong&gt; to run in the past three Presidential elections! Here are the facts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Politifact, a Pulitzer Prize-winning, independent fact-checking organization, determined that &lt;a href=&quot;https://datavizblog.com/2016/07/24/political-dataviz-who-lies-more-a-comparison-robert-mann/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hillary is the most truthful of all of the candidates who ran in 2016&lt;/strong&gt;, and ranks 2nd overall in a field of 20 presidential candidates, since 2007&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Just focusing on the general election candidates, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.politifact.com/truth-o-meter/lists/people/comparing-hillary-clinton-donald-trump-truth-o-met/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hillary is inarguably much more truthful&lt;/strong&gt; than Donald Trump&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Even one of her &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2016/mar/28/hillary-clinton-honest-transparency-jill-abramson&quot;&gt;long-time critics&lt;/a&gt; admits that Hillary is &lt;strong&gt;“fundamentally honest and trustworthy”&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;q-how-does-politifact-measure-truthfulness&quot;&gt;Q: How does Politifact measure truthfulness?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;: Politifact measures truthfulness on a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.politifact.com/truth-o-meter/article/2013/nov/01/principles-politifact-punditfact-and-truth-o-meter/&quot;&gt;six-point scale&lt;/a&gt;, from “True - The statement is accurate and there’s nothing significant missing” down to “Pants On Fire - The statement is not accurate and makes a ridiculous claim.” Here is how &lt;a href=&quot;https://public.tableau.com/views/WhoLiesTheMost-2016PresidentialElectionv92_0921_02/WhoLiesMostDashboard?:embed=y&amp;amp;:display_count=yes&amp;amp;:showVizHome=no&quot;&gt;Hillary matches up with some other prominent politicians&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hillary Clinton&lt;/strong&gt; - True: 22.90%; Mostly True: 27.86%; Half True: 22.13%; Mostly False: 14.50%; False: 10.31%; Pants On Fire: 2.29%. &lt;strong&gt;Hillary Clinton’s overall truthfulness is 72.89%&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bernie Sanders&lt;/strong&gt; - True: 13.21%; Mostly True: 38.68%; Half True: 19.81%; Mostly False: 16.98%; False: 11.32%; Pants On Fire: 0%. &lt;strong&gt;Bernie Sander’s overall truthfulness is 71.70%&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;President Barack Obama&lt;/strong&gt; - True: 20.57%; Mostly True: 27.49%; Half True: 26.81%; Mostly False: 11.64%; False: 11.97%; Pants On Fire: 1.52%. &lt;strong&gt;President Obama’s overall truthfulness is 74.90%&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mike Pence&lt;/strong&gt; - True: 15.4%; Mostly True: 7.7%; Half True: 34.6%; Mostly False: 15.38; False: 26.9%; Pants On Fire: 0%. &lt;strong&gt;Mike Pence’s overall truthfulness is only 57.70%&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Donald Trump&lt;/strong&gt; - True: 4.38%; Mostly True: 11.31%; Half True: 14.23%; Mostly False: 17.52%; False: 35.04%; Pants On Fire: 17.52%. &lt;strong&gt;Donald Trump’s overall truthfulness is only 29.92%&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;q-if-shes-not-a-liar-where-does-this-perception-come-from&quot;&gt;Q: If she’s not a liar, where does this perception come from?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;: Aside from the almost three decades of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.motherjones.com/politics/2014/06/hillary-clinton-conspiracy-theories&quot;&gt;conspiracy theories&lt;/a&gt; aimed at destroying her reputation, there may be a psychological component to this perception. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/the-fix/wp/2016/05/29/does-hillary-clinton-face-a-different-standard-for-honesty/&quot;&gt;Studies&lt;/a&gt; have shown that &lt;strong&gt;women are expected to be more honest than men&lt;/strong&gt;. According to Julie Dolan, professor of political science at Macalester College, and the lead author of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Women-Politics-Paths-Political-Influence/dp/0205827152&quot;&gt;Women in Politics: Paths to Power and Political Influence&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Because the generic female candidate is presumed more honest than the generic male candidate, voters judge a female candidate more harshly if she appears to violate the expectation of honesty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;q-but-what-about-her-e-mail-server-and-the-33000-emails-she-deleted&quot;&gt;Q: But what about her e-mail server and the 33,000 emails she deleted?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;: We actually have an &lt;a href=&quot;/issues/emails/&quot;&gt;article addressing Hillary’s private server&lt;/a&gt;. In short, Hillary did not break the law, and many of the widely circulated concerns have been addressed by the FBI.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 13:03:32 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://hillarymyths.org/issues/but-she-isnt-trustworthy/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://hillarymyths.org/issues/but-she-isnt-trustworthy/</guid>
        
        
        <category>deception</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>isn't the Clinton Foundation corrupt?</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;q-isnt-the-clinton-foundation-corrupt&quot;&gt;Q: Isn’t the Clinton Foundation corrupt?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;: No. The Clinton Foundation is a world-renowned charitable organization that has received top marks from independent charity watchdog groups. In &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cnn.com/videos/politics/2016/08/24/charity-watch-clinton-foundation-lv.cnn&quot;&gt;an interview with CNN&lt;/a&gt;, CharityWatch President Daniel Borochoff said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If Hillary Clinton wasn’t running for President, the Clinton Foundation would be seen as one of the great humanitarian charities of our generation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;q-what-do-these-independent-organizations-say-about-the-clinton-foundation&quot;&gt;Q: What do these independent organizations say about the Clinton Foundation?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;: Independent charity watchdog agencies have given the Clinton Foundation the &lt;strong&gt;highest ratings for transparency and accountability&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.charitywatch.org/ratings-and-metrics/bill-hillary-chelsea-clinton-foundation/478&quot;&gt;CharityWatch&lt;/a&gt; gave the foundation an &lt;strong&gt;A rating&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.charitynavigator.org/index.cfm?bay=search.summary&amp;amp;orgid=16680&quot;&gt;Charity Navigator&lt;/a&gt; gave them &lt;strong&gt;the highest possible rating, 4 stars&lt;/strong&gt;, with an incredible overall score of 94.74 out of 100.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.guidestar.org/profile/31-1580204&quot;&gt;GuideStar&lt;/a&gt; bestowed &lt;strong&gt;Platinum status on the Clinton Foundation, indicating the foundation’s commitment to transparency&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;q-ok-but-the-clintons-must-make-money-from-the-foundation-right&quot;&gt;Q: OK, but the Clintons must make money from the foundation, right?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;: Neither Hillary, Bill, nor Chelsea Clinton &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.clintonfoundation.org/about/frequently-asked-questions&quot;&gt;draw a salary from the Clinton Foundation&lt;/a&gt; or are otherwise compensated for their work for the foundation. Additionally:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A remarkable &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.charitywatch.org/ratings-and-metrics/bill-hillary-chelsea-clinton-foundation/478&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;88% of the funds&lt;/strong&gt; collected by the Clinton Foundation went to programs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2016/8/30/12690444/alma-powell-clinton-foundation&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;no evidence&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to support accusations that Clinton Foundation donors gained special access or favors from the State Department under Hillary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;q-what-is-the-clinton-foundation-anyway&quot;&gt;Q: What is The Clinton Foundation anyway?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;: The Clinton Foundation was founded by President Bill Clinton in 2001, to support the work of the Clinton Presidential Center, which contains his Presidential Library and supports the Arkansas community. He expanded the foundation’s role in 2002 to improve global access to HIV/AIDS treatment. The foundation has continued to grow and take on new challenges, including battling climate change, fighting childhood obesity, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.clintonfoundation.org/our-work/by-topic/girls-and-women&quot;&gt;increasing opportunities for women and girls&lt;/a&gt;, to name just a few.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;q-what-are-some-of-the-clinton-foundations-accomplishments&quot;&gt;Q: What are some of the Clinton Foundation’s accomplishments?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;: The Clinton Foundation &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hillaryclinton.com/feed/the-clinton-foundation-explained/&quot;&gt;saves lives and has helped millions of people worldwide&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The foundation has &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.politifact.com/global-news/statements/2016/jun/15/hillary-clinton/clinton-clinton-foundation-helped-9-million-lower-/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;helped 9 million people&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; get access to lower-cost medicine for HIV/AIDS.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Clinton Health Access Initiative partnered with governments to dispense lifesaving vaccines, which help &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.clintonfoundation.org/our-work/clinton-health-access-initiative/programs/accelerating-rollout-new-vaccines&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;save the lives of 50,000 children&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in Kenya, Ethiopia and Malawi each year.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In 2014, the Clinton Global Initiative launched Girls CHANGE in partnership with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.noceilings.org/&quot;&gt;No Ceilings&lt;/a&gt; and other organizations. Girls CHANGE has invested over $800 million, with the goal of helping 15 million girls by 2019.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Clinton Foundation, in partnership with Adapt Pharma, helped provide Naloxone, a drug that helps reverse the effects of heroin overdoses, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.usnews.com/news/articles/2016-01-25/overdose-reversal-drug-naloxone-offered-free-to-high-schools&quot; data-proofer-ignore=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;free of charge&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to all high schools in the United States.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Alliance for a Healthier Generation (which was founded by the American Heart Association and the Clinton Foundation), has helped bring &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.berkeley.edu/2015/06/03/healthy-schools-program-student-obesity/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;healthier food&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and more opportunities for physical activity to more than 18 million students in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.healthiergeneration.org/about_us/our_story/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;over 31,000 American schools&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, in every state.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 13:03:32 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://hillarymyths.org/issues/clinton-foundation-crooked/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://hillarymyths.org/issues/clinton-foundation-crooked/</guid>
        
        
        <category>trust</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>didn't she get a rapist acquitted, and then laugh about the girl who was raped?</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;q-didnt-hillary-get-a-rapist-acquitted-and-then-laugh-about-the-girl-who-was-raped-&quot;&gt;Q: Didn’t Hillary get a rapist acquitted, and then laugh about the girl who was raped?  &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;: In the second Presidential debate, Donald Trump claimed “Her client she represented
got him off and she is seen laughing on two occasions laughing at the girl who was raped.” This accusation &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.politico.com/blogs/2016-presidential-debate-fact-check/2016/10/trump-is-wrong-hillary-clinton-did-not-laugh-about-the-rape-of-a-12-year-old-229455#ixzz4MiTn0Cwt&quot;&gt;has been repeatedly disproven&lt;/a&gt;. Here are the facts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In 1975, Hillary was &lt;strong&gt;the court-appointed attorney&lt;/strong&gt; for a man being tried for the rape of a 12 year old girl.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The defendant &lt;a href=&quot;http://politicalticker.blogs.cnn.com/2014/06/25/prosecutor-in-controversial-case-says-clinton-had-no-choice-but-to-defend-rapist/comment-page-1/&quot;&gt;specifically requested a female attorney&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hillary was a young lawyer, only 27 at the time, and &lt;strong&gt;did not want to take the case&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;http://politicalticker.blogs.cnn.com/2014/06/25/prosecutor-in-controversial-case-says-clinton-had-no-choice-but-to-defend-rapist/comment-page-1/&quot;&gt;According to the prosecutor, Mahlon Gibson&lt;/a&gt;, Hillary approached him for advice:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;{Hillary said} ‘I don’t want to represent this guy. I just can’t stand this. I don’t want to get involved. Can you get me off?’ I told her, ‘Well contact the judge and see what he says about it,’ but I also said ‘don’t jump on him and make him mad.’ She contacted the judge and the judge didn’t remove her and she stayed on the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://constitution.findlaw.com/amendment6.html&quot;&gt;Sixth Amendment of the U.S. Constitution&lt;/a&gt; guarantees the right to an attorney. As a result, Hillary was &lt;strong&gt;obligated to defend her client to the best of her ability&lt;/strong&gt;, which she did. According to Gibson:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I would say she did a heck of a job of representing her client to the best of her ability. If you are appointed by the court, you damn better do everything you can do to defend them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The case resulted in a plea bargain, in which &lt;strong&gt;the defendant was convicted&lt;/strong&gt; of a lesser charge.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;q-but-how-could-hillary-laugh-at-a-girl-who-was-raped&quot;&gt;Q: But how could Hillary laugh at a girl who was raped?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;: Hillary did not laugh at the girl who was raped. In the mid-1980’s, Arkansas journalist, Roy Reed interviewed Hillary and asked questions about some criminal work she did as a lawyer. While discussing this case, Hillary is heard laughing about the polygraph test her court-appointed client took and about a conversation she had with the prosecutor about the poor forensic evidence available for prosecution. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.factcheck.org/2016/06/clintons-1975-rape-case/&quot;&gt;At no point did she laugh at or about the victim&lt;/a&gt;. Listen for yourself:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/e2f13f2awK4&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 13:03:32 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://hillarymyths.org/issues/defending-child-abuser/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://hillarymyths.org/issues/defending-child-abuser/</guid>
        
        
        <category>controversy</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>isn't she a criminal for using a private email server?</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;q-isnt-hillary-is-a-criminal-because-she-used-a-private-email-server&quot;&gt;Q: Isn’t Hillary is a criminal because she used a private email server?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;: No, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.politico.com/magazine/story/2016/09/hillary-clinton-emails-2016-server-state-department-fbi-214307&quot;&gt;an intensive FBI investigation&lt;/a&gt; concluded that there was &lt;strong&gt;no criminal wrongdoing.&lt;/strong&gt; On July 5th, FBI Director James Comey took the unprecedented step of publicly criticizing Hillary for her use of private emails. However, he went on to say that the FBI investigation showed that there was insufficient evidence of any criminal wrongdoing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;q-even-if-it-wasnt-a-crime-wasnt-it-against-department-of-state-regulations&quot;&gt;Q: Even if it wasn’t a crime, wasn’t it against Department of State regulations?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: There were &lt;strong&gt;no regulations against using a private email server&lt;/strong&gt; while Hillary was Secretary of State. During their investigation, FBI agents found there was “no restriction on use of personal email accounts for official business.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;q-ok-if-it-wasnt-a-crime-or-against-the-rules-she-was-still-negligent-and-exposed-government-secrets-to-the-world-right&quot;&gt;Q: OK, if it wasn’t a crime or against the rules, she was still negligent and exposed government secrets to the world, right?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: No. Consider these facts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The three emails Hillary received containing classified information were not properly marked to indicate their sensitive content. FBI Director James Comey stated that the emails lacked the proper headers and banners indicating they were classified. He went on to say that &lt;strong&gt;it would be a “reasonable inference” to assume that the emails were not classified.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hillary strongly preferred in-person conversations and printed documents to emails. &lt;strong&gt;Most of her communications were done outside of email.&lt;/strong&gt; To put things in perspective, of the approximately 40,000 emails sent and received on the private servers, &lt;strong&gt;only 0.0048 percent&lt;/strong&gt; of those emails were even in question.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hillary &lt;strong&gt;used &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sensitive_Compartmented_Information_Facility&quot;&gt;Sensitive Compartmented Information Facilities (SCIFs)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; throughout her tenure as Secretary of State. A SCIF is a secure area or room where sensitive information is viewed or discussed, and where secure telephone conversations are conducted. She even had SCIFs in her homes in Washington DC and Chappaqua, NY.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;q-if-she-had-nothing-to-hide-why-did-she-destroy-her-old-phones&quot;&gt;Q: If she had nothing to hide, why did she destroy her old phones?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: If Hillary had a government-issued Blackberry, it would have met a similar fate at the end of her tenure. Old government phones are  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/2016/09/actually-clinton-destroyed-phones-better/&quot;&gt;completely wiped clean and recycled, or they are destroyed&lt;/a&gt;. Jonathan Zdziarski, iOS forensics expert and security researcher, stated that if he were to destroy a Blackberry, he’d use “a blender and fire.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;q-and-why-did-she-delete-those-33000-emails&quot;&gt;Q: And why did she delete those 33,000 emails?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: FBI Director Comey explained that very well in his &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.c-span.org/video/?412315-1/fbi-director-james-comey-testifies-hillary-clinton-email-probe&amp;amp;live&quot;&gt;testimony to Congress&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;She actually had deleted some I think over time as an ordinary user would. And then the State Department contacted her and other former secretaries and said we have a gap in our records, we need you to look and see if you have e-mails and give them back. She then tasked her lawyers to engage in this review process of that 60 some thousand and make that cut and then was asked by her lawyers at the end, do you want us to keep the personal e-mails. And she said I have no use for them anymore. It’s then that they issued the direction that the technical people delete them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 13:03:32 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://hillarymyths.org/issues/emails/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://hillarymyths.org/issues/emails/</guid>
        
        
        <category>controversy</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>hasn't the establishment failed us?</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;q-hasnt-the-establishment-failed-us&quot;&gt;Q: Hasn’t the establishment failed us?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;: No. President Obama inherited a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.csmonitor.com/Commentary/Opinion/2009/0218/p09s02-coop.html&quot;&gt;financial&lt;/a&gt; disaster. And despite an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/republican-obstructionism-is-nothing-new/2016/02/15/2d856c12-d42c-11e5-b195-2e29a4e13425_story.html?utm_term=.7faadad9f0e1&quot;&gt;obstructionist Republican Congress&lt;/a&gt;, look at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2016/05/01/magazine/president-obama-weighs-his-economic-legacy.html?_r=0&quot;&gt;where we are now&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In 2009, unemployment reached a high of 10%; &lt;strong&gt;today it is 5%&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We’ve had &lt;strong&gt;73 months of private sector job growth&lt;/strong&gt;, the longest period on record.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Dow Jones Industrial Average was below 7,000 points in 2009, &lt;strong&gt;today it is over 18,000&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And contrary to what many people think, our &lt;strong&gt;federal deficit has declined by roughly three-quarters&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;q-how-has-the-current-administration-helped-regular-americans&quot;&gt;Q: How has the current administration helped regular Americans?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;: The Obama administration fought for legislation to create jobs, close the gender pay gap, help people with “underwater” mortgages keep their houses, and provide access to health coverage for millions of Americans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;President Obama pushed through the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2014/02/23/opinion/sunday/what-the-stimulus-accomplished.html?_r=0&quot;&gt;American Recovery and Reinvestment Act&lt;/a&gt;. The stimulus package prevented the United States from dipping back into recession. It &lt;strong&gt;created 1.6 million jobs a year for 4 years&lt;/strong&gt;, and raised the nation’s economic output by 2 to 3 percent from 2009 to 2011.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;President Obama’s first official act was to sign the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.whitehouse.gov/the-press-office/2016/01/29/fact-sheet-new-steps-advance-equal-pay-seventh-anniversary-lilly&quot;&gt;Lilly Ledbetter Fair Pay Act&lt;/a&gt; into law, which helped to &lt;strong&gt;close the pay gap between men and women.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The U.S. Treasury created the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.harp.gov&quot;&gt;Home Affordable Refinance Program (HARP)&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.makinghomeaffordable.gov/pages/default.aspx&quot;&gt;Making Home Affordable Program&lt;/a&gt;. Both programs &lt;strong&gt;help people impacted by the mortgage crisis keep their homes&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And perhaps President Obama’s crowning achievement, the Affordable Care Act (informally known as “Obamacare”), &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/to-your-health/wp/2016/01/07/more-than-11-3-million-americans-signed-up-for-obamacare-report-says/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;provides health insurance to 11.3 million people&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;q-is-there-more-to-do&quot;&gt;Q: Is there more to do?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;: Of course there is! Hillary will continue to move our country forward, and fight for even more programs to help Americans who are struggling. Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hillaryclinton.com&quot;&gt;detailed plans&lt;/a&gt; on her website.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 13:03:32 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://hillarymyths.org/issues/establishment-failed/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://hillarymyths.org/issues/establishment-failed/</guid>
        
        
        <category>obama</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>isn't she a war hawk?</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;q-isnt-hillary-a-war-hawk&quot;&gt;Q: Isn’t Hillary a “war hawk”?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;: No. A “war hawk” is considered to be someone who favors military use over diplomacy. That is absolutely NOT Hillary Clinton. Here are the facts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Hillary is a &lt;strong&gt;diplomat first&lt;/strong&gt;. As Secretary of State, she &lt;a href=&quot;https://mic.com/articles/21829/5-top-highlights-in-hillary-clinton-s-secretary-of-state-tenure#.x0B1Hndr6&quot;&gt;visited 112 different countries and logged almost 1,000,000 miles!&lt;/a&gt; Hillary negotiated a ceasefire between Israel and Hamas, helped open Burma to the rest of the world, and pushed the sanctions that finally got Iran to the negotiating table.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Yes, Hillary voted for the Iraq War in 2002. However, she and the other 76 Senators who voted Yes were &lt;strong&gt;told by the Bush administration that war would be the last resort&lt;/strong&gt;. On the Senate floor, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thepeoplesview.net/main/2016/3/20/hillary-clinton-is-not-a-hawk-foreign-policy&quot;&gt;Hillary explained the thought process behind her vote&lt;/a&gt; as bipartisan support that would bring more allies and legitimacy to the cause.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Sometimes military action is inevitable… and justified. For example, &lt;strong&gt;Hillary supported the raid that killed Osama bin Laden&lt;/strong&gt;. However, she chastised GOP Presidential nominees like Ted Cruz for their reckless and cavalier talk, such as &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.npr.org/2016/05/17/478361999/4-things-to-know-about-hillary-clintons-approach-to-foreign-policy&quot;&gt;“carpet bombing” ISIS&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Proposing that doesn’t make you sound tough. It makes you sound like you’re in over your head. Slogans aren’t a strategy. Loose cannons tend to misfire. &lt;strong&gt;What America needs is strong, smart, steady leadership to wage and win this struggle&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Even though the resolution before the Senate is not as strong as I would like in requiring the diplomatic route first… &lt;strong&gt;I take the President at his word that he will try hard to pass a United Nations resolution and seek to avoid war&lt;/strong&gt;, if possible. Because bipartisan support for this resolution makes success in the United Nations more likely and war less likely—and because a good faith effort by the United States, even if it fails, will bring more allies and legitimacy to our cause—I have concluded, after careful and serious consideration, that a vote for the resolution best serves the security of our nation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;q-what-are-the-facts-around-our-involvement-in-libya&quot;&gt;Q: What are the facts around our involvement in Libya?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt; As Secretary of State, Hillary also advocated for the NATO-led 2011 intervention in Libya that toppled Muammar Gaddafi. The intervention was launched to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nato.int/nato_static_fl2014/assets/pdf/pdf_2011_03/20110927_110311-UNSCR-1973.pdf&quot;&gt;protect Libyan civilians&lt;/a&gt;. At the time, Libya was engulfed in civil war, and Gaddafi was &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2011/02/23/world/africa/23libya.html&quot;&gt;threatening to massacre civilians&lt;/a&gt; protesting his regime, whom he called “cockroaches.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The intervention received broad support from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/government/speeches/prime-ministers-statement-on-libya--2&quot;&gt;European&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2011/feb/23/libya-nofly-zone-david-cameron&quot;&gt;allies,&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://edition.cnn.com/2011/WORLD/africa/03/09/libya.civil.war/&quot;&gt;Libyan rebels,&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2011/03/13/world/middleeast/13libya.html?pagewanted=all&amp;amp;_r=0&quot;&gt;Arab states,&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.washingtonpost.com/wp-dyn/content/article/2011/03/10/AR2011031004684.html&quot;&gt;Democratic&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://firstread.nbcnews.com/_news/2011/03/31/6382558-rubio-urges-regime-change-in-libya&quot;&gt;Republican&lt;/a&gt; members of Congress.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Hillary’s critics have made Benghazi a “rallying cry.” They’ve used the deaths of four American citizens, including U.S. Ambassador Christopher Stevens, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cnn.com/2015/10/14/politics/hillary-clinton-benghazi-committee/index.html&quot;&gt;to score political points&lt;/a&gt; and to paint Hillary as incompetent and hawkish. They’ve even &lt;strong&gt;admitted that the Benghazi investigations were politically motivated&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Representative Richard Hanna (R-NY):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This may not be politically correct, but I think that there was &lt;strong&gt;a big part of this investigation that was designed to go after people and an individual, Hillary Clinton&lt;/strong&gt;. After what Kevin McCarthy said, it’s difficult to accept at least a part of it was not. I think that’s the way Washington works. But you’d like to expect more from a committee that’s spent millions of dollars and tons of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this was Rep. Kevin McCarthy’s (R-CA) comment:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Everybody thought Hillary Clinton was unbeatable, right? But we put together a Benghazi special committee, a select committee. What are her numbers today? Her numbers are dropping. Why? Because she’s untrustable. But no one would have known any of that had happened had we not fought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;q-but-based-on-her-history-with-putin-wouldnt-hillary-be-more-likely-to-start-a-war-with-russia&quot;&gt;Q: But based on her history with Putin, wouldn’t Hillary be more likely to start a war with Russia?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;: No. In regards to U.S. relations with Russia, Hillary has a strong record of exploring diplomatic options and attempts to strengthen relations. As Russia increased air force activity at the beginning of the Ukraine crisis, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newsweek.com/where-do-clinton-and-trump-stand-russia-487777&quot;&gt;Hillary was asked if she would shoot down a Russian jet&lt;/a&gt;. She replied:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“That would not happen, because we’re going to put up a no-fly zone where the Russians are clearly kept informed,” Clinton said. “I want them at the table.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In 2009, Hillary was a key architect of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.whitehouse.gov/the-press-office/us-russia-relations-reset-fact-sheet&quot;&gt;the Russian reset&lt;/a&gt;, aimed at strengthening U.S.- Russia relations under the Russian Foreign Minister Sergei Lavrov. The reset encouraged the reduction of both the U.S. and Russian nuclear arsenal. As Putin returned to power, Hillary urged President Obama to take a tougher line with the Russian President. She called for &lt;a href=&quot;http://thehill.com/policy/international/212896-clinton-calls-for-tougher-sanctions-on-putin&quot;&gt;stricter sanctions on Russia after Malaysia Airlines flight 17 was shot down&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;During the 3rd Democratic debate, Hillary made it clear that she would want &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/the-fix/wp/2015/12/19/3rd-democratic-debate-transcript-annotated-who-said-what-and-what-it-meant/&quot;&gt;Russia included in a coalition to help destroy ISIS&lt;/a&gt;. She has repeated her stance that:&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;“There is an important role for Russia to help in resolving the conflict in Syria.”&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##Q: Why does Hillary support arming the Kurds in the war against ISIS?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;: The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.com/news/world-middle-east-29702440&quot;&gt;Kurds&lt;/a&gt; are a mostly Sunni Muslim people who live in the mountainous region of southern Turkey, western Iran, northern Iraq, and northern Syria. Here are some facts about the Kurds and their role in the war against ISIS:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The Kurds have been &lt;strong&gt;battling ISIS since the middle of 2013&lt;/strong&gt;. Since then, they have shown themselves to be one of our most effective partners in Syria and Iraq.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Most recently, the Iraqi Kurdish forces known as the peshmerga are playing a crucial role in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yahoo.com/news/peshmerga-fighters-tell-of-encounters-with-isis-while-others-wait-anxiously-for-their-turn-210034498.html&quot;&gt;battle for Mosul&lt;/a&gt;, Iraq’s second largest city and the Islamic State’s stronghold in that country. The Kurds and the Iraqi military, with assistance from U.S. special forces, and air support from the U.S., France, and Great Britain, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reuters.com/article/us-mideast-cris-iraq-mosul-idUSKCN12N0CA&quot;&gt;took back 80 villages&lt;/a&gt; from ISIS&lt;/strong&gt; in the first week of fighting alone.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;While the Kurds fight alongside the Iraqi army, as &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thedailybeast.com/articles/2016/10/21/on-the-mosul-front-where-kurds-fight-isis-with-bulldozers-and-pickups.html&quot;&gt;a recent news article&lt;/a&gt; points out, the peshmerga do not have anywhere near the same weapons and military equipment. And they are &lt;strong&gt;taking heavy casualties&lt;/strong&gt; as a result:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The MRAPs (mine-resistant ambush-protected vehicles), armored Humvees and German Dingos have been largely replaced by pickup trucks mounted with machine guns or light anti-aircraft cannons. The KRG has enjoyed some U.S. and European support, but has not been lavished with military hardware like the Iraqi army.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;As the Kurds fan out into enemy territory, this lack of protection begins to cost them. By the early afternoon, a steady stream of ambulances comes careening up the road. One of the advance columns has been attacked by a car bomb which succeeded in inflicting casualties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“They target the vehicles that do not have any armor,” says a Peshmerga who has accompanied a wounded comrade back from the front.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 13:03:32 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://hillarymyths.org/issues/hawk/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://hillarymyths.org/issues/hawk/</guid>
        
        
        <category>policy</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>isn't she cold, robotic, and unlikable?</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;q-why-is-hillary-so-cold-robotic-and-unlikable&quot;&gt;Q: Why is Hillary so cold, robotic, and unlikable?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;: Well, first of all, the real Hillary Clinton is none of those things. Just ask &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vox.com/a/hillary-clinton-interview/the-gap-listener-leadership-quality&quot;&gt;the people who know her&lt;/a&gt;. The Hillary that some people think is real is the result of decades-long attacks by her critics, and Hillary’s admitted discomfort with the process of campaigning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vox.com/a/hillary-clinton-interview/the-gap-listener-leadership-quality&quot;&gt;John Podesta&lt;/a&gt;, Chief of Staff to President Bill Clinton, Counselor to President Barack Obama, and Chairman of Hillary’s 2016 Presidential Campaign:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“You hear people say, ‘She’s so different in person.’ That’s what they’re finding so appealing. When people don’t know her well and they encounter her, people are taken with the fact that &lt;strong&gt;she is interested in them&lt;/strong&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://time.com/4424704/dnc-mothers-movement-transcript-speech-video/&quot;&gt;Lucia Bath&lt;/a&gt;, mother of Jordan Davis:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Hillary Clinton isn’t afraid to say black lives matter. She isn’t afraid to &lt;strong&gt;sit at a table with grieving mothers and bear the full force of our anguish&lt;/strong&gt;. She doesn’t build walls around her heart. Not only did she listen to our problems, she invited us to become part of the solution.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.demconvention.com/app_news/app_news_speeches/former-secretary-state-madeleine-albright-2016-dnc-speech/&quot;&gt;Madeleine Albright&lt;/a&gt;, former Secretary of State:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“She knows that &lt;strong&gt;safeguarding freedom and security is not like hosting a reality TV show&lt;/strong&gt;. It is a complex, round-the-clock job that demands not only a steady hand and a cool head, but also a big heart.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.realclearpolitics.com/video/2016/07/28/chelsea_clinton_introduces_hillary_at_dnc_she_never_forgets_who_she_is_fighting_for.html&quot;&gt;Chelsea Clinton&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“I never once doubted that my parents cared about my thoughts and my ideas, and &lt;strong&gt;I always knew how deeply they love me&lt;/strong&gt;. That feeling of being valued and loved — that is what my mom wants for every child. It is the calling of her life.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;q-so-where-does-the-myth-that-hillary-is-unlikable-come-from&quot;&gt;Q: So where does the myth that Hillary is unlikable come from?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;: The myth has two main origins: &lt;a href=&quot;https://decorrespondent.nl/5072/clinton-derangement-syndrome-diagnosing-the-real-reason-that-so-many-americans-hate-hillary/1434615793424-45000115&quot;&gt;decades-long attacks&lt;/a&gt; by Hillary’s critics; and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2016/09/25/opinion/sunday/hillary-clintons-angry-face.html?_r=0&quot;&gt;pressures placed&lt;/a&gt; on female public figures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For two and a half decades, Hillary has faced attacks on everything from her &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slate.com/articles/double_x/doublex/2015/11/hillary_clinton_hair_attacks_from_the_headband_to_the_wig.html&quot;&gt;hairstyles&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bustle.com/articles/86973-5-times-hillary-clintons-style-was-criticized-instead-of-her-ideas&quot;&gt;clothing choices&lt;/a&gt; to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.huffingtonpost.com/entry/complaining-hillary-clintons-voice_us_579add5de4b0693164c0b55c&quot;&gt;sound of her voice&lt;/a&gt;, her &lt;a href=&quot;http://mediamatters.org/blog/2015/10/14/media-return-to-deriding-hillary-clintons-laugh/206136&quot;&gt;laugh&lt;/a&gt;, and her &lt;a href=&quot;http://fortune.com/2016/09/27/hillary-clinton-smiling-debate/&quot;&gt;smile&lt;/a&gt; (or &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2016/09/09/us/politics/hillary-clinton-smiling.html&quot;&gt;absence of one&lt;/a&gt;). Even her &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cnn.com/2012/03/16/opinion/swinth-hillary-clinton/index.html&quot;&gt;cookie recipe&lt;/a&gt; created controversy.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If Hillary is perceived as too serious, she is labeled &lt;a href=&quot;http://nytlive.nytimes.com/womenintheworld/2016/09/08/clinton-criticized-for-not-smiling-enough-during-commander-in-chief-forum/&quot;&gt;“angry and defensive.”&lt;/a&gt; If she expresses passion for the causes she has fought for her whole political life, she is &lt;a href=&quot;https://thinkprogress.org/media-torn-over-whether-to-cast-clinton-as-weak-or-calculating-for-emotional-display-89faa9827964#.45qbd7hn2&quot;&gt;“too emotional.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;q-but-why-does-hillary-get-attacked-more-than-other-politicians-in-the-first-place&quot;&gt;Q: But why does Hillary get attacked more than other politicians in the first place?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2016/oct/18/hillary-clinton-why-hate-unlikeable-us-election&quot;&gt;The Guardian writes&lt;/a&gt; that Hillary Clinton’s perception as a ”militant feminist, difficult to deal with“ was largely related to people’s aversion to her feminist attitudes. The article goes on to quote Craig Shirley, a biographer and historian:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;He noted that she faced hostility in Arkansas politics and media when Bill Clinton was first elected governor, because she kept her maiden name. ”Here she comes, the feminist from Wellesley and Yale,“ Shirley explained […], ”down to Little Rock and brings her attitudes with her“.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time she arrived in D.C., Shirley explains, her reputation was already established.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;q-but-doesnt-politics-and-campaigning-come-naturally-to-her&quot;&gt;Q: But doesn’t politics and campaigning come naturally to her?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;: On the contrary, Hillary has acknowledged that &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.politico.com/blogs/2016-dem-primary-live-updates-and-results/2016/03/hillary-clinton-i-am-not-a-natural-politician-220544&quot;&gt;campaigning&lt;/a&gt; does not come easy for her. Nevertheless, those who &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chron.com/opinion/recommendations/article/For-Hillary-Clinton-8650345.php&quot;&gt;endorse&lt;/a&gt; Clinton &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.azcentral.com/story/opinion/editorial/2016/09/27/hillary-clinton-endorsement/91198668/&quot;&gt;note&lt;/a&gt; that her emotional restraint and poise under pressure would help make her an effective president&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those who know Clinton best can attest that she is an empathetic, caring individual. But more important, they confirm that &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vox.com/2016/7/27/12306702/democratic-convention-obama-hillary-clinton-bill-qualified&quot;&gt;she is ready&lt;/a&gt; to lead this country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“I can say with confidence &lt;strong&gt;there has never been a man or a woman — not me, not Bill, nobody — more qualified than Hillary Clinton to serve as President of the United States of America&lt;/strong&gt;.” - President Barack Obama&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 13:03:32 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://hillarymyths.org/issues/hillary-is-cold/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://hillarymyths.org/issues/hillary-is-cold/</guid>
        
        
        <category>personality</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>isn't she too sick to be president?</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;q-isnt-hillary-too-sick-to-be-president&quot;&gt;Q: Isn’t Hillary too sick to be President?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: No, Hillary is in excellent physical condition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2015, Hillary’s personal physician, Dr. Lisa Bardack, released a &lt;a href=&quot;https://m.hrc.onl/secretary/10-documents/01-health-financial-records/2015-07-28_Statement_of_Health_-_LBardack.pdf&quot;&gt;statement&lt;/a&gt; on her medical history. Bardack concluded:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Mrs. Clinton is a healthy 67-year-old female whose current medical conditions include hypothyroidism and seasonal pollen allergies…. She participates in a healthy lifestyle and has had a full medical evaluation, which reveals no evidence of additional medical issues or cardiovascular disease…. She is in excellent physical condition and fit to serve as President of the United States.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;q-then-what-happened-at-the-911-memorial&quot;&gt;Q: Then what happened at the 9/11 Memorial?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: On September 11, 2016, Hillary, who &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theatlantic.com/news/archive/2016/09/hillary-clinton-overheated/499514/&quot;&gt;had pneumonia,&lt;/a&gt; stumbled while leaving an event in New York City. Recovered, she &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.latimes.com/nation/la-na-pol-clinton-campaigning-20160915-snap-story.html&quot;&gt;returned to the campaign trail&lt;/a&gt; four days later. One of the most famous living journalists in United States history, Dan Rather, put &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/theDanRather/posts/10157417560045716&quot;&gt;this into context&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;But let’s be clear - barring any new developments this remains the story of a candidate working hard on the campaign trail who got a mild case of pneumonia and kept going when she maybe should have rested a bit. Everyone gets sick and until we have more proof of something severe, it remains a storyline to monitor but not belabor.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dan Rather has well over 40 years of context for Presidential campaigns; he ought to know what should be considered normal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;q-why-did-they-say-she-was-suffering-from-heat-exhaustion-rather-than-pneumonia&quot;&gt;Q: Why did they say she was suffering from heat exhaustion rather than pneumonia?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: Hillary’s illness at the 9/11 event was a result of overheating and overexertion, which is not uncommon when battling an infection like pneumonia. Thus the initial statement given by the campaign was accurate. Like many Americans, Hillary chose to continue working, even when ill, and did not share the information regarding her illness widely across the campaign. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nbcnews.com/politics/2016-election/hillary-clinton-falls-ill-9-11-memorial-n-y-n646376&quot;&gt;It was only after this incident that Secretary Clinton and her campaign chose to spread the news of her illness and have her doctor comment further on her condition.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 13:03:32 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://hillarymyths.org/issues/isnt-hillary-too-sick/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://hillarymyths.org/issues/isnt-hillary-too-sick/</guid>
        
        
        <category>health</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
