<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>I like Hillary But...</title>
    <description>I Like Hillary But... is a site designed to refute falsehoods and misconceptions about Hillary Clinton. Please pick your concern from the following list!
</description>
    <link>https://devprogress.us/i-like-hillary-but/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://devprogress.us/i-like-hillary-but/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>But isn't her experience all bad?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Q: Hillary has experience, but isn’t it bad experience?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: In the first Presidential debate, Donald Trump claimed that Hillary “has experience, but it’s bad experience.” This is utter nonsense. Hillary’s record of public service spans four decades, starting with her first job out of law school. Here are just a few examples of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hillaryclinton.com/feed/seven-hillary-clintons-biggest-accomplishments/&quot;&gt;Hillary’s many accomplishments&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fact&lt;/strong&gt;: As Secretary of State, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.politico.com/story/2012/11/clinton-announces-gaza-cease-fire-084145&quot;&gt;Hillary demonstrated her “shuttle diplomacy” skills&lt;/a&gt;. During a brutal period of violence, Hillary cut short a trip to southeast Asia and flew to the region. The bus bombing struck Tel Aviv as Hillary arrived to begin an intense round of shuttle negotiations. But &lt;strong&gt;within twenty-four hours, the ceasefire went into effect&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fact&lt;/strong&gt;: As Secretary of State, Hillary made &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hillaryclinton.com/issues/lgbt-equality/&quot;&gt;LGBT rights&lt;/a&gt; a focus of U.S. foreign policy. She fought for the first-ever U.N. Human Rights Council resolution on human rights and declared that &lt;strong&gt;“gay rights are human rights&lt;/strong&gt;.” She also made the State Department a &lt;strong&gt;better, fairer place for LGBT employees&lt;/strong&gt; to work.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fact&lt;/strong&gt;: Hillary &lt;strong&gt;worked with Republicans&lt;/strong&gt; to expand health care access for &lt;a href=&quot;http://correctrecord.org/hillary-clinton-a-record-of-service-to-veterans/&quot;&gt;members of the National Guard and reservists&lt;/a&gt;, making sure those who served and their families had &lt;strong&gt;access to health care&lt;/strong&gt; when they returned home. And she worked to &lt;strong&gt;expand the Family Medical Leave Act&lt;/strong&gt;, allowing families of those wounded in action to care for their loved ones.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fact&lt;/strong&gt;: Hillary had been the U.S. Senator from New York for just a few months when terrorists attacked us on 9/11. She worked tirelessly to make sure that the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nydailynews.com/news/politics/9-11-survivors-applaud-hillary-clinton-dnc-supportive-article-1.2727482&quot;&gt;9/11 first responders&lt;/a&gt; who suffered long term health effects from their time at Ground Zero &lt;strong&gt;got the care they needed&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fact&lt;/strong&gt;: In 1995, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/politics/first-draft/2015/09/05/20-years-later-hillary-clintons-beijing-speech-on-women-resonates/&quot;&gt;Hillary spoke at the United Nations 4th World Conference on Women&lt;/a&gt;. In this speech, she famously declared: &lt;strong&gt;If there is one message that echoes forth from this conference, let it be that human rights are women’s rights and women’s rights are human rights, once and for all!&lt;/strong&gt; As unaassuming as that sounds today, declaring that “women’s rights are human rights” was very controversial at the time. Many within the U.S. government didn’t want Hillary to go to Beijing at all. Others wanted her to pick a less “polarizing” topic. But Hillary would not be deterred; she was determined to speak out about women’s issues.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fact&lt;/strong&gt;: When Hillary was First Lady, she fought for health care reform. When that effort did not succeed, Hillary kept fighting. &lt;strong&gt;She worked with Republicans and Democrats&lt;/strong&gt; to help create the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.factcheck.org/2008/03/giving-hillary-credit-for-schip/&quot;&gt;Children’s Health Insurance Program&lt;/a&gt;. Today, CHIP &lt;strong&gt;provides health care to more than 8 million children&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fact:&lt;/strong&gt;  When Hillary graduated law school, she could have followed many of her peers and joined a prestigious law school. Instead, she chose to take a job with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hillaryclinton.com/feed/what-hillary-clintons-first-job-out-of-law-school-can-tell-us-about-who-she-is-today/&quot;&gt;Children’s Defense Fund&lt;/a&gt;, where &lt;strong&gt;she worked with teenagers incarcerated in adult prisons and families with disabled children&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 22:02:41 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>https://devprogress.us/i-like-hillary-but/issues/bad-experience/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://devprogress.us/i-like-hillary-but/issues/bad-experience/</guid>
        
        
        <category>experience</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>But Hillary wants my guns!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Q: But Hillary wants my guns!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: That’s not precisely correct!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, she doesn’t want your guns, unless you’re a felon, a
domestic abuser, or someone with severe mental illnesses. And I think
we can all agree that people like that shouldn’t really have access to
guns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s what her campaign &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hillaryclinton.com/issues/gun-violence-prevention/&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; says:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Expand background checks to more gun sales—including by closing the
gun show and internet sales loopholes—and strengthen the background
check system by getting rid of the so-called “Charleston Loophole.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Take on the gun lobby by removing the industry’s sweeping protection
for illegal and irresponsible actions (which makes it almost
impossible for people to hold them accountable), and revoking licenses
from dealers who break the law.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Keep guns out of the hands of domestic abusers, other violent
criminals, and the severely mentally ill by supporting laws that stop
domestic abusers from buying and owning guns, making it a federal
crime for someone to intentionally buy a gun for a person prohibited
from owning one, and closing the loopholes that allow people suffering
from severe mental illness to purchase and own guns. She will also
support work to keep military-style weapons off our streets.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 22:02:41 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>https://devprogress.us/i-like-hillary-but/issues/but-hillary-wants-my-guns/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://devprogress.us/i-like-hillary-but/issues/but-hillary-wants-my-guns/</guid>
        
        
        <category>guns,</category>
        
        <category>gun</category>
        
        <category>control</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>But isn't Hillary Clinton's foundation corrupt?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Q: Isn’t The Clinton Foundation corrupt?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: Nothing could be further from the truth. The Clinton Foundation is a world-renowned charitable organization, and has recieved top marks from independent charity watchdog groups. The only reason it is being attacked now is because Hillary Clinton is running for President.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, let’s take a quick look at the foundation’s history. The Clinton Foundation was founded by President Bill Clinton in 2001, originally to support the work of the Clinton Presidential Center, which contains his Presidential Library and supports the local Arkansas community. President Clinton expanded the role of the foundation in 2002 to help improve global access to treatment for people living with HIV/AIDS. Since then, the foundation has continued to grow and take on new challenges, including battling climate change, fighting childhood obesity, and increasing opportunities for women and girls, to name just a few.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hillaryclinton.com/feed/the-clinton-foundation-explained/&quot;&gt;interesting facts about the foundation’s work&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2/3rds of people who have received HIV/AIDS treatment throughout the world have been able to so because of the Clinton Foundation.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Clinton Health Access Initiative partnered with governments to dispense lifesaving vaccines, which help save the lives of 50,000 children in Kenya, Ethiopia and Malawi each year.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Clinton Foundation, in partnership with Adapt Pharma, helped provide Naloxone, a drug that helps reverse the effects of heroin overdoses, free of charge to all high schools in the United States.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Through the work of the Alliance for a Healthier Generation (which was founded by the American Heart Association and the Clinton Foundation), more than 18 million students in over 31,000 American schools, in every state, now have healthier food and more physical activity options.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A remarkable 87% of the funds collected by the foundation went to charity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So while Bill, Chelsea, and yes, Hillary have all been involved with the Foundation, none of them has taken a penny in compensation. Nor have they used it for the ridiculous “pay-to-play” allegations recklessly thrown around by her critics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But don’t take our word for it. Check for yourself with independent charity watchdog agencies. Agencies like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.charitywatch.org/ratings-and-metrics/bill-hillary-chelsea-clinton-foundation/478&quot;&gt;CharityWatch&lt;/a&gt;: who gave the foundation and A rating.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.charitynavigator.org/index.cfm?bay=search.summary&amp;amp;orgid=16680&quot;&gt;Charity Navigator&lt;/a&gt;: who gave them a 4 star rating, with an incredible overall score of 94.74 out of 100.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.guidestar.org/profile/31-1580204&quot;&gt;GuideStar&lt;/a&gt;: which bestowed Platinum status on the Clinton Foundation, indicating the foundation’s commitment to transparency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cnn.com/videos/politics/2016/08/24/charity-watch-clinton-foundation-lv.cnn&quot;&gt;an interview with CNN&lt;/a&gt;, CharityWatch President Daniel Borochoff said:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If Hillary Clinton wasn’t running for President, the Clinton Foundation would be seen as one of the great humanitarian charities of our generation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Clinton Foundation truly is a world-class humanitarian charity. And that’s not coming from Hillary Clinton, her campaign, or the Clinton Foundation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 22:02:41 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>https://devprogress.us/i-like-hillary-but/issues/clinton-foundation-crooked/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://devprogress.us/i-like-hillary-but/issues/clinton-foundation-crooked/</guid>
        
        
        <category>trust</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>But hasn't the establishment failed us?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Q: Why has the establishment failed us?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: “Are you better off now than you were four years ago?” Ronald Reagan first posed this question during the 1980 Presidential campaign, and Americans have been asking it themselves ever since. This is the final year of President Obama’s second term, so to cover his entire Presidency, let’s consider what the current administration has done over the past eight years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Has the establishment failed us? Take a look at just a small sampling of what the Obama Administration has accomplished and decide for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;President Obama’s first official act was to sign the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.whitehouse.gov/the-press-office/2016/01/29/fact-sheet-new-steps-advance-equal-pay-seventh-anniversary-lilly&quot;&gt;Lilly Ledbetter Fair Pay Act&lt;/a&gt; into law, which helped to close the pay gap between men and women.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;President Obama pushed through the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2014/02/23/opinion/sunday/what-the-stimulus-accomplished.html?_r=0&quot;&gt;American Recovery and Reinvestment Act&lt;/a&gt;. The stimulus package essentially prevented the United States from dipping back into recession. It created 1.6 million jobs a year for 4 years, and raised the nation’s economic output by 2 to 3 percent from 2009 to 2011. The package also improved 42,000 miles of roads and fixed or replaced 2,700 bridges. It cleaned up water supplies, created the school reforms of the Race to the Top program, and greatly expanded the use of renewable energy and broadband Internet service.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The Temporary Assets Relief Program (TARP) saved the financial and banking industries, and under President Obama’s leadership, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.politifact.com/new-hampshire/statements/2012/oct/25/barack-obama/barack-obama-says-banks-paid-back-all-federal-bail/&quot;&gt;virtually all of the “bailout” money was paid back&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.harp.gov&quot;&gt;Home Affordable Refinance Program (HARP)&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.makinghomeaffordable.gov/pages/default.aspx&quot;&gt;Making Home Affordable Program&lt;/a&gt; help people impacted by the mortgage crisis keep their homes.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And perhaps President Obama’s crowning achievement, the Affordable Care Act (informally known as “Obamacare”), &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.politico.com/story/2014/03/obamacare-affordable-care-act-104540&quot;&gt;provides health insurance to 4.2 million people&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, are people better off now than they were in 2009? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2016/05/01/magazine/president-obama-weighs-his-economic-legacy.html?_r=0&quot;&gt;Most Americans are&lt;/a&gt;. Here are some facts about the health of our economy:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In 2009, unemployment reached a high of 10%; today it is 5%.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We’ve had 73 months of private sector job growth, the longest period on record.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Dow Jones Industrial Average was below 7,000 points in 2009, today it is over 18,000.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And contrary to what many people think, our federal deficit has declined by roughly three-quarters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is there more to do? Of course there is! And Hillary will continue to move our country forward, and fight for even more programs to help Americans who are struggling. Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hillaryclinton.com&quot;&gt;detailed plans&lt;/a&gt; on her website.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 22:02:41 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>https://devprogress.us/i-like-hillary-but/issues/establishment-failed/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://devprogress.us/i-like-hillary-but/issues/establishment-failed/</guid>
        
        
        <category>obama</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>But isn't she a war hawk?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Q: Isn’t Hillary a “war hawk”?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: No. A “war hawk” is considered to be someone who favors military use over diplomacy. That is absolutely NOT Hillary Clinton. Here are the facts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fact:&lt;/strong&gt; Hillary is a &lt;strong&gt;diplomat first&lt;/strong&gt;. As Secretary of State, she &lt;a href=&quot;https://mic.com/articles/21829/5-top-highlights-in-hillary-clinton-s-secretary-of-state-tenure#.x0B1Hndr6&quot;&gt;visited 112 different countries and logged almost 1,000,000 miles!&lt;/a&gt; Hillary negotiated a ceasefire between Israel and Hamas, helped open Burma to the rest of the world, and pushed the sanctions that finally got Iran to the negotiating table.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fact:&lt;/strong&gt; Yes, Hillary voted for the Iraq War in 2002. However, she and the other 76 Senators who voted Yes were &lt;strong&gt;told by the Bush administration that war would be the last resort&lt;/strong&gt;. On the Senate floor, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thepeoplesview.net/main/2016/3/20/hillary-clinton-is-not-a-hawk-foreign-policy&quot;&gt;this is how Hillary explained the thought process behind her vote&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Even though the resolution before the Senate is not as strong as I would like in requiring the diplomatic route first…&lt;strong&gt;I take the president at his word that he will try hard to pass a United Nations resolution and seek to avoid war&lt;/strong&gt;, if possible. Because bipartisan support for this resolution makes success in the United Nations more likely and war less likely—and because a good faith effort by the United States, even if it fails, will bring more allies and legitimacy to our cause—I have concluded, after careful and serious consideration, that a vote for the resolution best serves the security of our nation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fact:&lt;/strong&gt; Hillary’s critics have made Benghazi a “rallying cry.” They’ve used the deaths of four American citizens, including U.S. Ambassador Christopher Stevens, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cnn.com/2015/10/14/politics/hillary-clinton-benghazi-committee/index.html&quot;&gt;to score political points&lt;/a&gt; and to paint Hillary as incompetent and hawkish. They’ve even &lt;strong&gt;admitted that the Benghazi investigations were politically motivated&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Representative Richard Hanna (R-NY):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This may not be politically correct, but I think that there was &lt;strong&gt;a big part of this investigation that was designed to go after people and an individual, Hillary Clinton&lt;/strong&gt;. After what Kevin McCarthy said, it’s difficult to accept at least a part of it was not. I think that’s the way Washington works. But you’d like to expect more from a committee that’s spent millions of dollars and tons of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this was Rep. Kevin McCarthy’s (R-CA) comment:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Everybody thought Hillary Clinton was unbeatable, right? But we put together a Benghazi special committee, a select committee. What are her numbers today? Her numbers are dropping. Why? Because she’s untrustable. But no one would have known any of that had happened had we not fought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fact:&lt;/strong&gt; Sometimes military action is inevitable…and justified. For example, &lt;strong&gt;Hillary supported the raid that killed Osama bin Laden&lt;/strong&gt;. However, she chastised GOP Presidential nominees like Ted Cruz for their reckless and cavalier talk, such as &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.npr.org/2016/05/17/478361999/4-things-to-know-about-hillary-clintons-approach-to-foreign-policy&quot;&gt;“carpet bombing” ISIS&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Proposing that doesn’t make you sound tough. It makes you sound like you’re in over your head. Slogans aren’t a strategy. Loose cannons tend to misfire. &lt;strong&gt;What America needs is strong, smart, steady leadership to wage and win this struggle&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 22:02:41 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>https://devprogress.us/i-like-hillary-but/issues/hawk/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://devprogress.us/i-like-hillary-but/issues/hawk/</guid>
        
        
        <category>policy</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>But Hillary Clinton cold, robotic, and unlikable</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Q: Why is Hillary so cold, robotic, and unlikable?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: Well, first of all, the real Hillary Clinton is none of those things. Just ask the people who know her. The Hillary that some people think is real is the result of decades-long attacks by her critics, a psychological phenomena, and Hillary’s admitted discomfort with the process of campaigning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine being in the public eye, at a national and even world-wide level, since 1992. Imagine that you had a vocal group of people that critized everthing you did, every word that came out of your mouth, every new hair style and clothing choice, the sound of your voice, your laugh, and your smile. Even her &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cnn.com/2012/03/16/opinion/swinth-hillary-clinton/index.html&quot;&gt;cookie recipe&lt;/a&gt; created controversy. No kidding. That is the scrutiny that Hillary Clinton has faced for almost three decades.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even before entering the public spotlight, Hillary learned that, as a woman, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.humansofnewyork.com/post/150127870371/i-was-taking-a-law-school-admissions-test-in-a&quot;&gt;she needed to keep her emotions in check&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I know that I can be perceived as aloof or cold or unemotional, but I had to learn as a young woman to control my emotions. And that’s a hard path to walk. Because you need to protect yourself, you need to keep steady, but at the same time you don’t want to seem ‘walled off.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Donald Trump has no similar constraints. Frankly, no other Presidential candidate ever has. If Hillary is perceived as too serious, she is labeled “angry and defensive.” If she expresses passion for the causes she has fought for her whole political life, she is “too emotional.” But why is that? Well, &lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/journals/emo/9/5/649/&quot; data-proofer-ignore=&quot;true&quot;&gt;one study&lt;/a&gt; indicates that it’s because we perceive men and women differently. In this study, subjects were shown pictures of the faces of men and women in various poses. The subjects were asked if the person in the picture was likely being emotional, or responding to a situation. The study showed that in most cases, the women were said to be emotional, while the men were reacting to a situation. Unfortunately, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2016/09/25/opinion/sunday/hillary-clintons-angry-face.html?_r=0&quot;&gt;these stereotypes are playing out in this election&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And to top it off, Hillary knows that she is not &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.politico.com/blogs/2016-dem-primary-live-updates-and-results/2016/03/hillary-clinton-i-am-not-a-natural-politician-220544&quot;&gt;a natural politician&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I am not a natural politician, in case you haven’t noticed, like my husband or President Obama. I have said before and it won’t surprise anybody to hear me say it, this is not easy for me. It’s not easy to do what I think is right to help people, to even the odds…and to know that I can make a difference and I want to in every way possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But cold? Robotic? Unlikable? These are not words those who know Hillary would ever use to describe her. On the contrary, those who know and have worked with (and for) her describe Hillary as &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vox.com/a/hillary-clinton-interview/the-gap-listener-leadership-quality&quot;&gt;“brilliant,” “funny,” “thoughtful,” “effective,” and “a listener.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are quotes from people who know the real Hillary Clinton:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“You hear people say, ‘She’s so different in person.’ That’s what they’re finding so appealing. When people don’t know her well and they encounter her, people are taken with the fact that she is interested in them.” - John Podesta, Chief of Staff to President Bill Clinton, Counselor to President Barack Obama, and Chairman of Hillary’s 2016 Presidential Campaign&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Hillary Clinton isn’t afraid to say black lives matter. She isn’t afraid to sit at a table with grieving mothers and bear the full force of our anguish. She doesn’t build walls around her heart. Not only did she listen to our problems, she invited us to become part of the solution.” - Lucia Bath, mother of Jordan Davis&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“She knows that safeguarding freedom and security is not like hosting a reality TV show. It is a complex, round-the-clock job that demands not only a steady hand and a cool head, but also a big heart.” - Madeleine Albright, former Secretary of State&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“I never once doubted that my parents cared about my thoughts and my ideas, and I always knew how deeply they love me. That feeling of being valued and loved — that is what my mom wants for every child. It is the calling of her life.” - Chelsea Clinton&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yes, even Donald Trump had praise for Hillary Clinton, before he became her Republican challenger:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“I think Hillary Clinton could do whatever she puts her mind to. I really do. She’s incredibly dedicated to public service, she is smart as a whip, and she’s effective.” - Donald Trump&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hillary is truly a kind, friendly, and yes, likable person. But none of that is as important as being ready and able to lead this country. And that makes Hillary not only the better choice, but perhaps the best ever:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“I can say with confidence there has never been a man or a woman — not me, not Bill, nobody — more qualified than Hillary Clinton to serve as President of the United States of America.” - President Barack Obama&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 22:02:41 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>https://devprogress.us/i-like-hillary-but/issues/hillary-is-cold/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://devprogress.us/i-like-hillary-but/issues/hillary-is-cold/</guid>
        
        
        <category>personality</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>But isn't Hillary too sick to be president?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Q: Isn’t Hillary too sick to be President?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: No. While personal health is a consideration when choosing a
President, Hillary &lt;strong&gt;is a healthy woman&lt;/strong&gt;, who happens to have some mild
health conditions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To expand further (references in links):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2015, Hillary’s personal doctor released this
&lt;a href=&quot;https://m.hrc.onl/secretary/10-documents/01-health-financial-records/2015-07-28_Statement_of_Health_-_LBardack.pdf&quot;&gt;statement&lt;/a&gt;.
Several key snippets from this include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Mrs. Clinton is a healthy 67-year-old female whose current medical
conditions include hypothyroidism and seasonal pollen allergies”,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“She exercises regularly, including yogo, swimming, walking, and
weight training”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“She participates in a healthy lifestyle…”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On September 11, 2016, Hillary had
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/clinton-falls-ill-during-911-memorial-service-in-new-york/2016/09/11/a52e09c2-7855-11e6-ac8e-cf8e0dd91dc7_story.html&quot;&gt;an incident in New York City&lt;/a&gt;. One
of the most famous living journalists in United States history, Dan
Rather, put
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/theDanRather/posts/10157417560045716&quot;&gt;this into context&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;But let’s be clear - barring any new developments this remains the
story of a candidate working hard on the campaign trail who got a
mild case of pneumonia and kept going when she maybe should have
rested a bit. Everyone gets sick and until we have more proof of
something severe, it remains a storyline to monitor but not belabor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dan Rather has well over 40 years of context for Presidential
campaigns: he ought to know what should be considered normal.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 22:02:41 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>https://devprogress.us/i-like-hillary-but/issues/isnt-hillary-too-sick/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://devprogress.us/i-like-hillary-but/issues/isnt-hillary-too-sick/</guid>
        
        
        <category>health</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>But isn't she for free trade?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Q: Doesn’t Hillary support trade agreements that take jobs away from American workers?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: Not at all. Trade deals are complex because they are supposed to benefit all of the nations involved. However, Hillary strongly believes that all trade deals must benefit American workers, first and foremost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider the facts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fact:&lt;/strong&gt; Hillary isn’t wholly pro-trade or anti-trade. Instead, &lt;strong&gt;she evaluates each trade deal on its merits and determines the overall benefit to American workers&lt;/strong&gt;. As &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.politifact.com/truth-o-meter/statements/2016/apr/10/bernie-s/clinton-voted-virtually-every-trade-agreement-kill/&quot;&gt;Gene Sperling, director of the National Economic Council in the Clinton and Obama administrations&lt;/a&gt; put it:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Some people are generally pro-trade or anti-trade. She’s case-by-case on trade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fact:&lt;/strong&gt; As U.S. Senator from New York, Hillary voted for roughly half of trade deals that came before her. However, she voted against the &lt;a href=&quot;https://scout.sunlightfoundation.com/item/speech/CREC-2005-06-30-pt2-PgS7697.chunk96/sen-hillary-clinton-senate&quot;&gt;Dominican Republic-Central America Free Trade Agreement(DR-CAFTA)&lt;/a&gt;, saying:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;While this agreement provides some benefit for New York, I regretfully conclude &lt;strong&gt;the harm outweighs the good.&lt;/strong&gt; I must therefore vote to oppose…Sadly, DR-CAFTA is a step backward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fact:&lt;/strong&gt; Like &lt;strong&gt;Senator Bernie Sanders&lt;/strong&gt;, Hillary voted against the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.politifact.com/truth-o-meter/statements/2016/apr/10/bernie-s/clinton-voted-virtually-every-trade-agreement-kill/&quot;&gt;Trade Act of 2002&lt;/a&gt;. This legislation extended the Andean Trade Preference Act, but also gave the President fast track authority to negotiate trade deals. Fast track authority means that when the President negotiates a trade deal, Congress can only vote for or against it.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fact:&lt;/strong&gt; Hillary did not “flip flop” on TPP. Yes, Hillary did originally support the Trans-Pacific Partnership, or TPP. However, when the final deal was finished, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ontheissues.org/2016/Hillary_Clinton_Free_Trade.htm&quot;&gt;it did not benefit American workers the way she thought it should&lt;/a&gt;. As a result, she felt obligated to oppose it:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I have always fought for the same values and principles, but, like most human beings–including those of us who run for office–I do absorb new information. I do look at what’s happening in the world. Take the trade deal. I did say, when I was secretary of state, three years ago, that I hoped it would be the gold standard. It was just finally negotiated last week, and in looking at it, it didn’t meet my standards. My standards for more new, good jobs for Americans, for raising wages for Americans. And &lt;strong&gt;I want to make sure that I can look into the eyes of any middle-class American and say, “this will help raise your wages.”&lt;/strong&gt; And I concluded I could not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fact:&lt;/strong&gt; Hillary is &lt;strong&gt;not a die-hard supporter of the North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA)&lt;/strong&gt;. Back in 2007, Hillary had &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ontheissues.org/Archive/2007_AFL-CIO_Dems_Free_Trade.htm&quot;&gt;this to say&lt;/a&gt; at the AFL-CIO Democratic Primary Forum:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I had said that for many years, that NAFTA and the way it’s been implemented has hurt a lot of American workers. In fact, I did a study in New York looking at the impact of NAFTA on business people, workers and farmers who couldn’t get their products into Canada despite NAFTA. So, clearly we have to have a broad reform in how we approach trade. NAFTA’s a piece of it, but it’s not the only piece of it. &lt;strong&gt;I believe in smart trade. Pro-American trade. Trade that has labor and environmental standards&lt;/strong&gt;, that’s not a race to the bottom but tries to lift up not only American workers but also workers around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 22:02:41 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>https://devprogress.us/i-like-hillary-but/issues/trade/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://devprogress.us/i-like-hillary-but/issues/trade/</guid>
        
        
        <category>policy</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
